TIAGO O. DE FARIAS

PHP SYSTEMS ANALYST / DEVELOPER

DATE OF BIRTH

12 September 1985

CONTACT

TELEPHONE

51 9 9292 2705

E-MAIL

tiago.farias.poa@gmail.com

SOCIAL NETWORKS

github.com/tofarias bitbucket.org/tiagofarias tiagoodefarias.wordpress

facebook.com/laravelrgs

linkedin.com/in/tiago-farias1985

ADDRESS

Rua Doutor José Bento Corrêa, 545 Bairro Protásio Alves, CEP: 91450-030 Rio Grande do Sul. Porto Alegre,

Brazil

SKILLS

PHP 5 / 7	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
Laravel	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
TDD / BDD	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
S.O.L.I.D / GRASP	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
GIT/SVN	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
CakePHP	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
Linux	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
Oracle	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
Apigility	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	
Zend Expressive	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	*	

OBJECTIVE

Acting in the development / analysis of PHP systems, database, requirements survey and agile methods.

ABOUT ME

I am Brazilian, professional with more than 6 years of experience in software development. For a number of years i've been working on the study and application of S.O.L.I.D./GRASP principles and code refactoring, more recently i'm dedicated to the study of Domain-Driven design which was also the subject of my graduation work.

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

2014 - 2016Postgraduate UniRitter

Information Systems with Agile Methods

Main topics: Agile Development Practices, Design Patterns, Smells and Refactoring, Web Architectures, Agile Software Testing, Project Management, Agile Coaching and Mentoring. Article Title: "Aplicação de Domain-Driven Design no Gerenciamento de GRU de Cronotacógrafo no Inmetro/RS". https://github.com/tofarias/artigoddd/blob/master/artigo/artigo-domain-drivendesign.pdf

Advisor: M.e. Guilherme Silva de Lacerda. Adress: Rua Orfanotrófio, 555 - Alto Petrópolis,

Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

2010 - 2013Graduation Faculdades QI

Systems Analysis and Development

Main topics: Web Services, Project Management, Software Security, Software Engineering, Java Development O.O. Adress: Av. Julho de Castilhos, 435 - Centro,

Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

2008 - 2010Certificate **Programs**

Faculdade QI

Computer Technician

CERTIFICATES / EVENTS

iMasters Certified Professional April / 2017

PHP - Good Practices

JavaScript ********
/ JQuery

Languages (according European Union Council)

English A2 Spanish A1 http://certificacao.imasters.com.br/users/tiag

o-oliveira-de-farias

August / 2017 TreinaWeb Zend Expressive – PHP Microframework

September / 2017 TreinaWeb PHP: BDD - Behat

August / 2017 TreinaWeb **PostgreSQL - Developer**

October / 2017 TreinaWeb **PostgreSQL - DBA**

2015 UniRitter TDC - The Developer's Conference

2012 Academic Week

Faculdade QI Participated as panelist - PHP: Codeigniter e

Lumine

2011 **Projeto Crescer**

CWI Training with SQL Server, .Net and Java

2011 **PHP Training**Target Trust Zend Framework
2011 **Volunteer Work**

Faculdade QI Monitoring in the discipline of Algorithms and

Programming

EXPERIENCE

PHP Programmer

07/2017 - hoje RZ2 Sistemas de Gestão (TECHNOLOGY COMPANY) Focused on the development of REST APIs following the JsonApi.org specification. Develops with the framework Lumen (Laravel) and Doctrine. Acts in the "Easy Train" project "gamification" software. Responsible for applying integration and deploy tests with the Jenkins tool and load tests with JMeter.

05/2017 – 06/2017 DITECH (TECHNOLOGY COMPANY)

PHP Programmer

Acting in clientes projecrts at John Deere's bank.

PHP Analyst / Programmer

03/2015 - 05/2017 ADVANCEDIT (TECHNOLOGY COMPANY) Allocated in the Inmetro client (federal agency). Mainly works with the PHP language (CakePHP) and Oracle database in the Chronotachograph project. Performed from requirement survey through user interviews to impact analysis along with database administrators.

Systems Analyst

08/2013 – 03/2015 CONSTRUTORA PELOTENSE (ENGINEERING COMPANY) I worked on the development of an internal web system that aims to manage contracts and invoices of works. The invoice module is loaded with information from the database (SQL Server) managed by the TOTVS system: RM and Flows. Developed with PHP (Laravel), TDD, Git, in linux environment along with MySql database.

01/2013 – 08/2013 CONSTAT

PHP Programmer

I worked mainly with the PHP language. Responsible for developing

(TECHNOLOGY COMPANY)

requirements analysis, project documentation, TDD development.

Computer Technician

05/2012 – 12/2012 EMATER / ASCAR (STATE AGENCY) Computer recunician

Ingressou mediante concurso público, atuando na manutenção de computadores nos escritórios municipais. Eventualmente desenvolveu programas em Java para auxiliar nas demandas do setor.

solutions for the Qualitor product and its modules. Performed

Le

Programmer PHP / .Net

05/2011 – 04/2012 CWI (TECHNOLOGY COMPANY) In April / 2011, the CWI Software project, which took place in São Leopoldo, was developed in the "Crescer" project. The 2-month training involved the following technologies: SQL Server 2008, ASP.Net, C Sharp, Java Web. With the end of "Crescer" project I continued in the company as a trainee working on technical support at São Leopoldo headquarters with PHP / Zend Framework for client "TUV Rheinland" and CodeIgniter for Terra client, I was transferred to the unit in Porto Alegre joining the client project "Odebrecht", using dotNet technologies MVC and PL / SQL, then joined the development team for SENAC / RS client in the project to develop the company's intranet using dotNET MVC and SqlServer 2008.